

MALAY CHANDAN

Software Engineer

Enthusiastic Software Engineer with 5 years of experience participating in the complete product development cycle of successfully launched web applications. Gained proficiency with a wide-variety of programming languages & developed in-depth knowledge of the latest technologies as a result of working on numerous complex projects. Looking forward to applying the acquired gamut of skills to a challenging software development role.

mlychndn@gmail.com



07073590523



New Town, India

WORK EXPERIENCE

IT Analyst

Tata Consultancy Services

06/2022 - Present

Hyderabad,

JavaScript Developer NA Sportz Interactive

09/2021 - 05/2022

Developer

Cognizant Solution Pvt. Ltd.

01/2018 - 09/2020

PROJECTS

Bayer GCS-Proxy

- Developed search engine for Bayer using google search api.
- Have created many featues for Bayer search like advance filtring, pagination, indexing and sorting, prioritization according to country wise.
- Used Google Cloud App Engine for deploying the app.
- Developed features like multiple keywords seach and prioritization using node.js
- Done CRUD operation using dataStore of Google Cloud
- Done servral unit testing

Widget Library

- Sports project developed from scratch.
- Developed Tennis widget for Austatalian Open for clients SonyLiv, WWOS, Fairfax
- Developed Football, F1-racing and Cricket widget for clients WWOS and bet2ball
- Used node.js and Vue.js to build the widget
- Have done several unit testing

The Natours App:

- Transportation & Hospitality Project developed from scratch.
- Developed Restful APIs and Implemented MVC model.
- Conceptualised and implemented plan to integrate APIs for 10+ partners using Node.js.
- Implemented payment gateway and file sharing APIs using different npm packages like multer stripe etc.
- Implemented security authentication APIs.
- Developed different models using MongoDB database.
- Have done unit testing of different functionality using mocha and chai.

EDUCATION

BE Bit Mesra

07/2013 - 07/2017

Courses

Electrical And Electronics

SKILLS

Technical Skills: HTML, CSS, BOOTSTRAP, JAVASCRIPT, NODE JS, MONGODB, SQL, GIT, UNIX, ETL, Google Cloud, Git Lab

Database Management: Oracle 11g/12c, MongoDB

Research and Planning: Identifying Problems, Gathering Information, Devolping **Evalutions, Calculating Results**

Soft Skills: Leadership, Optimistic, Flexibility,

CERTIFICATES

SQL (09/2020 - 09/2020)

I have taken the assesment at Hackerank and passed the assesment and got certified.

Complete Oracle Certification course (05/2020 - Present)

Completed oracle certification training from udemy and got certified by udemy

JAVASCRIPT (12/2020 - 12/2021)

I have taken the assesment on cutshort and passed the assesment and got certified.

Linux Training Course (09/2020 - Present)

Completed linux training from udemy and got certified by udemy

The Complete 2020 Web Developement Bootcamp certification (12/2020 - Present)

Completed web developement of more than 70 hours with hands on and developed 16 projects within the course

LANGUAGES

English

Professional Working Proficiency

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

INTERESTS

Swimming

kabaddi

body building